AMEER ALHASNAWI

CONTACT

Address: High Point, NC 27265

Phone: (336)875-1051

Email: ameer.usa1986@gmail.com

WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

- Portfolio: https://ameerportfolio2023.netlify.app/
- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ameer86
- Frontend Mentor: https://www.frontendmentor.io/profil e/Ameerusa86

SKILLS

- Express JS
- MERN Stack
- React JS
- HTML & CSS
- JavaScript
- Android App Development using JAVA.
- CSS Frameworks: Sass, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS & Material UI
- jQuery
- Next JS
- Redux
- Git & GitHub

EDUCATION

Master of Science: Information Technology, Expected in 04/2023 Southern New Hampshire University - Manchester

- Honor Roll for 22TW1 term in 2022
- Honor Roll for 22TW4 term in 2022
- Honor Roll for 22TW5 term in 2022
- 3.8 GPA
- Capstone Project: Drug Addiction, creating a website and mobile application
 with a database that supports connecting those in need of addiction
 treatment to centers and practitioners who are immediately available.

Bachelor of Science: Mechatronics Engineering, 09/2008 **Baghdad University of Technology** - Iraq

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Detail-oriented, organized, and meticulous employee. Works at a fast pace to meet tight deadlines. Enthusiastic team player ready to contribute to company success.

Consistently recognized for dependability and multi-tasking skills. Supported company business objectives and strategies while gaining real-world experience.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

IT Analyst II, 02/2022 to Current EMSIMC - Winston-Salem, NC

- Off-boarding/terminating user computers by restoring the system to base configuration, upgrading to current standards, and preparing for redeployment.
- Onboard new employees by connecting the computer's physical components and configuring the operating system to access the First Point network, which may include upgrading the hardware and software. Determine which software, tools, and access rights new hires need based on business divisions' systems requirements.
- Respond to tickets in person, by email, or over the phone.
- Perform remote troubleshooting through diagnostic techniques and pertinent questions.
- Determine the best solution based on the issue and customer details.
- Install and test desktop applications, including complex or custom installations.
- Understand, monitor, and identify misapplication of corporate governance guidelines related to hardware and software.

Network Support Specialist, 10/2021 to 02/2022 Northstate Technology Solutions - High Point, NC

- Monitored network hardware operations to evaluate proper configuration.
- Performed network security design and integration duties.
- Improved overall user experience through support, training, troubleshooting, improvements, and communication of system changes.
- Identified issues and implemented troubleshooting techniques to alleviate downtime and system failure.
- Gathers data and monitors customer impact as needed for outages and maintenance on the network to keep management apprised.
- Learns quickly and retains and recalls product information while handling multiple priorities in a fast-paced environment.

Maintenance Technician /Supervisor, 06/2018 to 10/2021 Mill-Chem Manufacturing - Thomasville, NC

- Executed tasks within time and budget constraints.
- Reported issues to the property manager so effective resolutions could be implemented.
- Inspected, tested, and adjusted mechanical and electrical systems to facilitate proper functioning.
- Installed new locks, door handles, and door closers.
- Repaired and replaced pumps, valves, and motors.
- Inspected and maintained equipment to keep items in top working condition.
- Followed work orders and machine and equipment replacement, repair, or maintenance specifications.

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures from free Code Camp
- Responsive Web Design from free Code Camp
- Cisco Certified Network Associate Routing and Switching (CCNA)
- AWS Academy Graduate AWS Academy Cloud Foundations
- Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert (MCSE): Core Infrastructure
- Microsoft Certified Systems Administrator: Microsoft Dynamics 365
- MCSA: Windows Server 2016 Certified 2020
- Google IT Support Professional Certificate
- CompTIA A+ ce Certification
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Administrator Associate